# Christy (Yiran) Chen Data Analyst | Business Analyst

Dedicated, result-oriented and knowing why & how Analyst with experience in CRM, financial analyses, data analytics and Data visualization. Apart from possessing exceptional analytical and problem solving skills, Christy is a great team player with strong communication and presentation skills.

C: 647-936-7015

E: yiranc52@gmail.com

A: Toronto

## **TECHNICAL (IT) SKILLS**

Database Design & Management, Strong in Data Profiling, Integration, Cleansing and Data Quality Data Assessment, Reconciliation, Pattern and Trend Identification Management

Advanced SQL, Pyspark in SQL Server & Cloud Snowflake, Databricks to create DDL, DML & Analytics Queries Computer Data Cleansing using Python, R, Advanced Excel, Access & VBA; Jira, Confluence, ServiceNow, draw.io Science

Operational reporting and Analytical Dashboard design and development using Report

Dashboard Excel Reporting Automation, PowerBI and other Self-Serve BI Tools, such as Google Analytics and Tableau

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Data Analyst | EDPYPF Service Incorporated

Oct 2022 - Present

- Analyzed industry trends and customer data in Cloud Snowflake database and validated the data integrity gaps.
- Prepared ad hoc and ongoing Power BI reports for clients, designed Customer Loyalty Assessment dashboard
- Automated reporting process by introducing technical solution to reduce repeated work in Excel using VBA
- Monthly Financial income statement report automation process design and development
- Data Quality analysis, summarized the method to resolve duplication issue in data warehouse
- Processed data using MS Access & Excel with dynamic analyzing model for ensuring effectiveness of job delivery

## INTERN EXPERIENCE

## Data Analyst | ZGC Smart City Co. Ltd

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Participated project The Last line of defense (Patients contact tracker); updated the newly reported COVID cases using MySQL, visualized patients' relationships via Neo4j, spotted risky areas to prevent expansion of infection chain
- Gathered 200k+ data from the Bureau of Real Estate Management and the Bureau of Statistics of City, created tables and updated data using PostgreSQL, and organized data using Python

## **Investment Analyst | Galaxy Securities**

May 2022 - Jul 2022

- Cleaned and analyzed product transactional data in Excel and R; identified the correlation among sales data, stock market index, Consumers' attitude through regression analyses
- Submitted a first listing day analytical report on real estate investment trust (REIT) through Wind financial database

### **Customer Support | HUAXIA Bank**

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

- Consulted with clients regarding loan prime rate (LPR) conversion and advised over 100 owners on their decisions
- Helped clients open credit cards, and recommended financial products to clients based on their financial needs

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Bellabeat Smart Device Marketing Strategy Analyses & Visualization

Jul 2022 - Aug 2022

Statistical model based Gender Bias Investigation with data wrangling - Black Saber Software Inc.

May 2021

Bell strategies to accelerate prepaid gross subscriber additions

May 2022

Market Share Analysis – Big Buy Retail Sales

Jan 2022

Digital Marketing – Campaign KPI determination & Analyses

Nov 2022

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATE**

Bachelor of Science

**University of Toronto** 

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Statistics & Economics; Computer Programming, Method Data Analysis, Financial Economics

Certification: Google Data Analytics Professional, Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python